# **TAYON WILLIAMS**

### Full Stack Developer | Software Engineer

864-337-1201 | tayondw@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Frontend:** React.js, React Native, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Backend:** Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python

Other Tools and Technologies: Google Maps API, Socket.io, AWS S3, yfinance API, Docker, Git, Flask, Alembic, Postman, Figma, Canva Relevant Skills: Data Analysis, Client Management, Technical Design, Code Review, Pair Programming, Object Oriented Programming

#### PROJECTS

MenCryToo, Full Stack Developer - React | Docker | Python | Flask | AWS S3 | PostgreSQL

Live | Repo

\*The project is currently being updated to include new features such as the Google Maps API, FastAPI, and Mental Treat API. These additions will provide real-time data, enhancing user access and efficiency.

- Designed a full-stack app where the user can join groups, attend events, create a profile with issue-specific tags, and post sharing using full CRUD operations to ensure a perfect user experience.
- Incorporated AWS for a seamless user experience of real-time communications of chatting and photo-sharing.
- Enhanced the application's efficiency, dynamism, and maintainability utilizing React Router DOM loaders and actions as a streamlined alternative to Redux.

Ravenhood, Full Stack Developer - React | Docker | Python | Flask | SQLAlchemy | AWS S3 | yfinance API | PostgreSQL

Live | Repo

- Leveraged the yfinance API to import and seed real-time stock data allowing the construction of the entire site for user accounts.
- Developed a full-stack app with React/Redux frontend and Flask/SQLAlchemy backend for efficient data synchronization and CRUD operations.
- Coordinated project utilizing Kanban methodology within a team to effectively organize tasks, track progress, and ensure timely completion of all required features, resulting in a fully functional and optimized web application.

# MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCE

Senior Sales Manager | Orakel Marketing, Columbia, SC

August 2019-June 2020

- Collaborated with senior leaders to promote marketing materials and scale Internet services' prices and usage, leading to month over month organic growth on internet and cable services by 84% and 24%.
- Managed a sales team of ten and secured three accounts in one week with revenue of \$10,000 total.
- Developed strategies involving competitor analysis for services, leading to an increase of sales to 50+ clients per month.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# Quality Control Chemist III | Element Materials Technology, Santa Rosa, CA

April 2022-December 2022

- Refactored maintenance of QC SOPs, test methods, analytical validations, reference standard qualification, and stability studies.
- Supervised qualification and calibration of analytical equipment and/or approval of calibration results.
- Designed and developed a spreadsheet to record the consumption, purpose, and location of reference standards for maintenance.

### Quality Control Chemist I | The Ritedose Corporation, Columbia, SC

June 2020-December 2021

- Conducted trend analysis for out-of-specification results, identifying issues to reduce analyst error from 34% to 15% within a year.
- Wireframed a chemical inventory location sheet to decrease downtime in production due to constant searching for chemicals.
- Successfully supported and led three analytical method validations and transfers within a three-month timeframe.

### Analytical Chemist | Colgate-Palmolive, Hodges, SC

July 2017-August 2019

- Architectured a beginners training document for analytical instruments to assist new hires in instrument operation as System Manager.
- Assisted with managing a budget of \$250,000 on reagents and LIMS equipment through ordering and arranging training from vendors.
- Conducted training sessions for personnel, ensuring their understanding and precise adherence to Standard Operating Procedures.

# **EDUCATION**

App Academy, Software Engineering

Online

The University of Georgia, Bachelor of Science in Chemistry - Minor: Spanish

Athens, GA

# COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Google x Career Karma's Black Genius Academy: A Tech Equity Collective, Member Men Cry Too, Founder

October 2023

July 2023

**UGA Alumni Association, Member** 

May 2017